If there's one single highest leverage
skill you can learn to radically
transform the quality of your life for
better, it's content creation.
I want to show you a clip from 2017,
and this was the first time I'd ever
spoken to camera. [upbeat music] Oh,
how we doing?
Do I look big?
I feel like I'm being
interviewed. You got the job already,
James.
You signed on the line.
There's no need to be nervous.
My name's James Smith.
I'm a personal trainer from England,
from the UK, near Windsor.
Recently moved to Australia to come to the
center of the fitness
industry to take over. You could tell
that my mannerisms, my ability to
talk to camera,
they've improved quite a lot since,
and so has the quality of my
life. Now,
I think you maybe don't have the right
relationship with social
media. You might think that we
are just posting videos for people to
watch,
and that couldn't be further from the
truth.
This morning,
I got a refund request from someone,
said that what I was teaching
was too surface level. And I thought,
"Wow,
I've got someone really advanced here.
Let me have a look at your Instagram."
Zero posts.
Now, chances are, if you're watching this,
the hardest hurdle is to go from zero to
one. And ultimately,
I think the reason you haven't started
posting content yet is
because you maybe don't fully understand
what you're about to get into.
And if you did, you'd be posting.
First of all,
let's remove it from context.
Let's imagine you
are creating a play in the theater.
And by the way, I hate that shit.
I'd rather wank off my grandad than go to
the
theater. Just throwing it out there.
When people are like, "Oh, it
was fantastic." Shut up.
Anyway, for the theater,
you have to put together a play.
You have to cast, you have to rehearse,
you have to get it perfect.
And on the night, you've got a crowd,
they've paid money to be in there, and
if you
don't get it right, you're a failure.
They're going to write an article in the
local newspaper, and your name will be
tarnished forever.
But in the world of social media,
you can create a piece of
content that's average or not that good,
and it just won't really get seen that
much. That's how the algorithm works.
It'll be given to a small amount of
people, and based on how they react,
it will go
further and further wide. Quite literally,
every single social media platform wants
your next video to get a billion views,
but it's just not good enough yet.
And nor should it be.
You've just got into this.
Similar to when I started in
that clip before.
How can you be good at something
that you've not done much? It's retarded.
In almost every realm online,
when you have to create something,
should it not be good, there
are big repercussions.
Let's say you release an album.
People don't like the music.
Big repercussions.
Let's even look at mistakes.
If you come in the wrong woman
and she has your children, big mistake.
You have an affair, get divorced,
big mistake. You go drink driving,
big mistake.
But to record a video on this,
I say something wrong, I go back,
I edit it out.
I put the version of the video up.
I didn't quite get the hook
or the setup right.
I make it again in a few weeks.
Whereas in life, there
are really bad mistakes, the
mistakes I make on here give me real-time
feedback into skill acquisition,
something I'm trying to get better at,
and I have unlimited attempts to get
better
over whatever period of time I like with
no negative repercussions.
But it's not only that. Any of you
that are a Type A personality, care about
attention to detail,
you want to get the most out of life.
Maybe you're entrepreneurial,
aspirational, whatever it is.
You're looking for the best use of your
time, energy, and effort.
Now, some of you, you might even invest,
and I've never really been mad on it.
I was having an argument with a friend six
months ago.
He said, "You need to invest in stocks
and shares." I said,
"All right." I put in,
what, 110 grand? It's gone up 3.25%, and
I'm sorry, but that's pathetic.
And people say, "Oh, you could average
9% to 12%." To me, that's not good.
For that 100K, I could have done so much
more.
I could have taken any one of you watching
this, built you a studio.
Bought you that camera.
Hired you two members of staff full time,
and
got you to producing content for your
business, five videos a day.
One of them scripting,
one of them editing.
Six months, and I'm up three
and a half grand. That's pathetic.
From 100K, I could have done so much.
Yet this is where we're telling people,
work jobs you don't like.
Have bosses you hate to squirrel money
into investments where you get a few
percent back.
I'm barely beating inflation.
You can invest into property.
You'll lump your stamp duty,
pay capital gains on the way out.
You can invest into local businesses,
whatever it is.
But why is no one telling you that
if you invest into content creation
twofold, yes, financially, buy a camera,
get a good microphone, maybe get a light.
But two, invest,
as in pay in on a repetitive
basis consistently over time with making
fucking
videos.
You can put in £5 a day to the S&P 500,
but you can also put one video out on
social media. And guess what?
In both scenarios, fuck all
is going to happen for a couple of years.
But let me tell you this. The moment
that that investment changes
the way your life works happens a lot
quicker in the content creation
side because I can't really manipulate the
S&P 500.
And that is influenced by pandemics, war,
whatever it is.
But I can quite literally get away with
insider trading over here by coming up
with
good ideas,
emulating what's working for my
competitors, running campaigns.
Becoming better at the skill of
communicating to camera.
Right now, 10 minutes ago,
I sat here without any idea of what I
was going to talk
about.
I jotted down some notes on my screen.
I'm now creating this.
This is a digital asset. This
is a creative piece of art with one thing
in
mind. You are my audience,
and I don't want you to sit there and go,
"Oh, bravo.
That's some of the best acting I've ever
seen.
Fucking 'Romeo and Juliet's' never looked
so good." I'm here with one
objective in mind,
to get you to fucking start posting
content.
And I'm not doing it because I make money
from it.
Well,
some of you buy Short-Form Content
Mastery.
There'll be a link in the description.
I'm doing it to actually accrue goodwill
because in three years' time, you're going
to start to realize, holy shit,
this works.
This is the best investment ever.
If you could only truly understand the
potential
returns on content creation,
you'd be doing it already.
That's why the video's here. Does
that make sense?
You've been brainwashed somewhere along
the way, and you post a video, and you say
it only got 400 views.
Let me tell you this.
If I put you in a room with 400 people
and get you to present, you'd shit your
fucking pants. Imagine pre-internet
and pre-social media, I take
Tony Robbins back in his heyday, go, "Hey,
mate.
Can you imagine a world where I get you to
be seen by a million people and it
happens for free?" How? Social media.
How do I get to a million people?
Well,
you just make a good piece of content.
How do I make a good piece of content?
Well,
there's going to be the experience element
where you know and understand the
game.
There's also going to be the self-levels
of competence that you grow over
time. Should you master both of those,
you could do really well.
Traditional investing in the S&P 500
is put it away and don't do anything with
it
for 30 years. 30 years,
I'm going to be fucking 67, 68.
Be an old man.
That video was 2017.
First time I ever spoke to a professional
camera.
It's now 2016.
It's not even been 10 years.
I live in a nice house on the beach.
Drive a GT3.
I haven't flown economy-Me long haul in
eight or nine years.
I fly my family business class
and first class wherever they go.
My fiancée doesn't have to work.
I buy my parents a car,
and I pay for their
mortgage.
And it's not because I'm special.
It's not because I'm naturally talented.
It's because I decided to go all in on
content creation.
The idea of squirreling money away for 30
years never excited me.
The idea of investing in a startup
that wasn't mine hasn't really
interested me.
Building an audience of thousands of
people that want to buy my
stuff does interest me,
and it should interest you too.
Now, for a lot of you watching this,
you may not know this yet,
but you probably
aren't going to do what you're doing now
forever. It might be something similar.
If you have an established accountancy
firm or you're a lawyer,
you probably will.
But some of you,
let's say personal trainers, coaches,
physios, whatever, there's
going to come an opportunity in your life
and you're going to pivot.
And you're going to take all the skills
that you learned from the three years
before to the three years ahead,
and you're going to take them with you.
And it's in your best interest
that content creation is one of those.
For instance, I worked in sales
and marketing before becoming a personal
trainer.
I took those skills into that next role.
And as a personal trainer with the skills
in sales and marketing, I took that into
social media. Chris Williamson,
my business partner in Nutonic, he
was a club
promoter before.
And I'm sure he had many events
that started off quiet, and he was
like, "Look, if we do the promotions,
if we make it a good night,
and everyone that
comes brings a friend,
we will get exponential growth from that."
And he ran a
successful nightclub business,
and he put the same thing into his
podcast, now one
of the world top 10 podcasts. Now,
if I was to tell you that you
were going to
change careers in three years
and do something completely different,
something way
better than what you're doing now,
do you really think
that becoming a content
scientist in the next three years would be
a waste of time?
And by content scientist,
I mean a video does well,
you ask yourself why.
A video does poorly, you ask yourself why.
Someone else does something differently,
you ask yourself why.
Someone else does something badly,
You try something that they've done,
it does well, you ask yourself why.
We are scientists of everything, really.
Even when you're in a relationship,
there are constant micro changes.
You're trying to figure out your
boundaries. Say something,
you get a bad reaction.
Say something, you get a good reaction.
It's the same in the content game.
Now, what they don't tell you
is the first year's going to suck.
There's going to be posts you delete.
There's going to be embarrassment,
judgment from friends, whatever.
But this is the highest leverage skill
ever in human history.
It is the best return on investment where
you don't even have to have spare capital
to put it in.
You just need a device to record yourself
on, iPhone, DJI
camera, whatever it is,
a skill set to share with the internet,
and the
persistence and grit
and tenacity to keep it going
and not expect anything for the
first year. Now,
back to the person who asked for a refund.
I said, "All right.
I'll refund you on one condition,
that you do the work and it doesn't
work." I said, "Do 100 videos.
If your life hasn't completely changed,
come back.
I'll refund you in full." I'm going to say
the same thing to you.
I said to the guy, "Look, it's win-win.
Either the 100 videos change your life,
or you get your money back." I said, "You
paid me to make you start making content,
so here you go.
You're still going to get the refund,
but you got to do the fucking work first."
I
said, "Do the work,
and you can have the refund." So there you
go.
There's an insurance policy.
Short-Form Content Mastery,
link in the description.
You buy that. Over the next 100 posts
that you put out, either your life is
drastically changed and you're like,
"Fuck me,
this is the best investment ever,"
or I send you your fucking cash back.
If you've already bought it, that's fine.
You can check out this video here for more
information. Start fucking posting.
Being a fucking pussy could be the biggest
cost and gravest error of
your life. Oh, Jesus. Bye.